ABHISHEK CHANDRASHEKAR

abhishekcs007@gmail.com | Linkedin.com/abhishekcs007

Software developer with 4+ years of experience. Specialized in developing full stack applications using Java, JavaScript, SQL and the related frameworks. Experienced with implementing Big Data Solutions using Java, Python and Google Cloud Platform.

SKILLS

Languages Java, JavaScript, Python, SQL

Backend Frameworks Struts2, Spring Boot

Frontend Frameworks React, jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS
Cloud Tools Azure, Google Cloud Platform

Testing Libraries TestNG, Selenium

Databases MSSQL Server, MySQL

Version control tools Git, SourceTree

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

Agilisium Consulting | Mar 2022 – Present

- Developed features in an application using React, Spring Boot and Google cloud APIs to get insights about Airflow pipeline status and Google dataflow Jobs
- Designed and developed pipelines from scratch to clean, normalize and ingest big data from multiple sources and different file formats using Python, Airflow and Google cloud platform
- Leveraged Google Cloud APIs to automate manual tasks such as backfills, data quality checks, data refresh which reduced manual workload by 20%
- Optimised several existing queries and procedures to reduce costs
- Developed complex queries to derive new tables containing accurate KPIs for multiple partners using Big Query

Software Engineer

Object Frontier Software | Jul 2018 - Feb 2022

- Developed complex logics related to invoice generation and payment processing in a monolith application using Struts2, Spring Boot, Java
- Designed and developed several pages in frontend to handle various use cases related to invoice generation and reporting using Redux, JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap
- Developed REST and SOAP APIs to expose the features of invoicing application to third party clients
- Integrated functionality to invoicing application from third party application by using their APIs
- Ensured 100% end-to-end test coverage of all modules in the web application using selenium
- Designed and developed REST APIs for a web application to handle the training and development activities within the organization using Spring boot

CERTIFICATIONS

AZ – 204: Microsoft Azure Developer Associate

Microsoft

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications Rajalakshmi Engineering College 2014 - 2018